<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>La Sobremesa</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://lacroqueta.me/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-24T03:19:23.033Z</updated>
  <id>http://lacroqueta.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jason Zheng</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Shot on iPhone</title>
    <link href="http://lacroqueta.me/2019/01/24/Shot%20on%20iPhone/"/>
    <id>http://lacroqueta.me/2019/01/24/Shot on iPhone/</id>
    <published>2019-01-24T03:16:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-24T03:19:23.033Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Preparing…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Preparing…&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Photos" scheme="http://lacroqueta.me/tags/Photos/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>张江一室户租房指南</title>
    <link href="http://lacroqueta.me/2018/12/18/%E5%BC%A0%E6%B1%9F%E4%B8%80%E5%AE%A4%E6%88%B7%E7%A7%9F%E6%88%BF%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97/"/>
    <id>http://lacroqueta.me/2018/12/18/张江一室户租房指南/</id>
    <published>2018-12-18T08:14:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-19T12:27:51.860Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="前言"><a href="#前言" class="headerlink" title="前言"></a>前言</h2><p>从十一月份开始，我在张江找了近一个月的房子。要求是独立的一室户，洗手间干湿分离。期间基本把张江这一带符合要求的房子都跑遍了。正好最近有朋友也有类似的需求，那就分享一下经验吧。</p><p>张江这边能提供一室户的主要有三大类：商业公寓，人才公寓，以及民用住宅。</p><ul><li><p>商业公寓主要有城家公寓、泊寓、盛大天地青春里、绿地 M Town、万科翡翠公园。这些都是开发商或自己新建或承包已有的老住宅楼自己办的公寓。各家与各家之间不太一样，底下会详谈。</p></li><li><p>人才公寓指张江人才公寓，属于公租房。一般来讲都是周围符合要求的上班族或引进的人才通过申请才能拿到，排队时长大多都在一年到两年不等。有一些人在排到的时候，由于自己本身的房子还有租约，或者嫌麻烦不想搬，一般会选择转租。<br>  这种还是存在一定的风险，因为按规定是不允许转租的，网络上还有消息说会有人不定期查房登记。有可能今天人家查了，明天就得搬。不过也有许多人住在里面并没有出现过问题。有的人才公寓会存在最长租期的问题，因为政策原因，可能房东本人只能签两年，到期之后就不能续租了，或是一定期限以后房东公司发的补贴停止，所以租金会有上涨。看房的时候需要问清楚。但由于租金较为便宜，且邻居素质普遍不差，所以还是可以考虑一下的。<br>  人才公寓有好几个，转租比较多的主要是高科苑、天之骄子、张江豪臣汤园以及复旦人才公寓。</p><p>  <img src="/2018/12/18/张江一室户租房指南/maps.png" alt="&quot;张江人才公寓分布图&quot;"></p></li><li><p>民用住宅基本都是好几室的那种，一户承包一间卧室或客厅，（有机率）共用洗手间和厨房。基本分布在张江核心区周边，且都是成片的大住宅区，生活气息浓厚，公共交通拥挤。比较有名的如孙桥镇附近的川杨新苑、申城佳苑、玉兰香苑，及张江镇上大片的老小区。</p></li><li><p>万科翡翠公园和张江豪臣汤园的情况比较特殊，都有公寓和民住的部分。下文里会谈到。</p></li></ul><p>由于我自己不愿意和别人合租，所以基本只看了非合租的一室户。下面来讲一讲。</p><a id="more"></a><h2 id="商业公寓"><a href="#商业公寓" class="headerlink" title="商业公寓"></a>商业公寓</h2><h3 id="城家公寓"><a href="#城家公寓" class="headerlink" title="城家公寓"></a>城家公寓</h3><p>城家公寓在张江附近有两家，一家在蔡伦路科苑路（一般简称“科苑路店”），一家在蔡伦路伽利略路（一般简称“蔡伦路店”）。它家属于直接和公寓签约，app 上可以在线签约、交租金、交水电。水电每个月1号会出账单，10 号前要付清，可以看到水和电分别用了多少，但无法查看每天或一定时间段的量。长短租混合。长租是半年起租，押三付一的价格比押一付一便宜一些。租期内换房间要支付小几百的手续费。</p><h4 id="蔡伦路店"><a href="#蔡伦路店" class="headerlink" title="蔡伦路店"></a>蔡伦路店</h4><p>城家公寓蔡伦路店位于药谷蔡伦路伽利略路附近，被汉庭和全季两家酒店包围。由于周围都是公司，所以周末及晚上人烟十分稀少。楼下只有一个小超市，一个两三家面馆/馄饨店/饺子店，环境非常一般。其中有一家清真面馆，所以经常会有伊斯兰人士聚集，晚间还是比较可怕的。有三条去 2 号线金科路站及张江高科站的公交，上下班高峰挺挤的。步行五分钟左右能到有轨电车站。虽然位置比较偏僻，但肯德基麦当劳盒马都能送到，外卖选择也比较多。<br>公寓一楼有办公室，可以代收快递，门口也有快递柜。我住在这里半年的时间出现过一次快递丢失的情况。公寓内走道很窄，各户之间挨得很近，隔音比较差。每两层有一台洗衣机和烘干机。<br>房间内装潢尚可，配有冰箱微波炉电视。洗手间干湿分离。不通煤气天然气。<br>面积从 30 平不到到 40 多平都有，租金 3000 多到 4000 ，物业费另算，200 到 300 。商业水电，电一块多钱一度，冷水不要钱，热水 40 元/吨。</p><h4 id="科苑路店"><a href="#科苑路店" class="headerlink" title="科苑路店"></a>科苑路店</h4><p>城家公寓科苑路店位于科苑路蔡伦路附近，交通位置比较好，离 2 号线张江高科站步行只有 1000 米距离。楼下也有有轨电车站，公交线路也有好几条。旁边就是上海中医药大学、上外附属浦东外国语学校、上海电影艺术学院和复旦张江校区（远一些也有交大张江校区及上科大）。配套丰富，餐饮娱乐都是学生价。当然楼下就是黑暗料理一条街，气味及噪音是缺点。楼下有免费健身房和公共娱乐空间。<br>这家城家不是嫡系的，貌似是承包的老住宅楼后改成公寓的。所以房间普遍都很小，装潢比较简陋，洗手间也很简陋，同时租金较贵。配洗衣机冰箱（微波炉有没有我记不得了）。房间我感觉只有十几二十几平，租金基本在 4000 以上。商业水电。</p><h3 id="万科翡翠公园"><a href="#万科翡翠公园" class="headerlink" title="万科翡翠公园"></a>万科翡翠公园</h3><p>万科翡翠公园在上科大东边，分为住宅和公寓。公寓我去看过一次，基本都是两到三室。也有房东隔下来的一室户，门口一道大门后是两道小门。隔音应该比较一般。楼下有快递柜。这边的房子基本都是要和房东谈，楼下中介很多。隔下来的一室户 20 平左右，租金在 3500 以上。<br>离金科路较远，过川杨河基本都要走金科路，另外一条哥白尼路过川杨河的桥还在修。没有汽车没有自行车的话交通会不太方便。听说有班车去金科路站。年底 13 号线中科路站即将开通，会稍微好一些。<br>万科的优势在于自带商业体，生活气息十分浓厚。我还在上学的时候就喜欢来这边的 2049 商场来玩，里面餐饮面包房理发店一应俱全，属于社区类的小型商场，人不多，但是很温馨。万科的住宅也是非常贵的，邻居素质应该普遍较高。住宅没遇见过分租的情况。</p><h3 id="泊寓"><a href="#泊寓" class="headerlink" title="泊寓"></a>泊寓</h3><p>泊寓在张江也有两家，一家在万科翡翠公园，一家在张江国创中心。泊寓是万科旗下的品牌，形式和城家公寓比较相似，但品质比城家好不少。但房子普遍较小，且租金较高。</p><h4 id="万科翡翠公园店"><a href="#万科翡翠公园店" class="headerlink" title="万科翡翠公园店"></a>万科翡翠公园店</h4><p>泊寓万科翡翠公园店就在 2049 商场的对面。周边配套自不必说。楼下有免费健身房和公共娱乐空间，我去看房的那天正好有 LOL 的比赛，很多男生就在楼下聚在一起观看。住户基本都是周围的上班（IT）族。走廊比较宽阔，暖系装潢风格。房间内许多家具也都是木质的，洗手间干湿分离，且装潢不错。没有微波炉洗衣机冰箱。有的房间比较小，需要把床抬起来才能通过。小的房子，二十平左右，租金在 4000 上下。稍微宽敞一些的，租金可能会上 4500 甚至 5000。商业水电。</p><h4 id="张江国创中心店"><a href="#张江国创中心店" class="headerlink" title="张江国创中心店"></a>张江国创中心店</h4><p>有同学暑期在这边短住过一段时间，所以我也去看了看。国创中心离张江核心区稍微远了一些，距离 2 号线广兰路站有 1.5 公里的距离，但附近有一座有轨电车站。那边属于新建不久的综合体，周围空间比较广阔，有一些餐饮，全家星巴克等也都有。还有一家很大的书店，装潢十分漂亮，有点钟书阁的感觉。与万科那边温馨的环境相反，这边从周边到公寓内都有一种金属现代风的感觉。走廊是黑灰色的，房间内也是偏冷静一点。楼下有免费健身房。同样也是没有微波炉洗衣机冰箱。总体来说，房间不如万科店，租金比万科点稍微便宜一点点，但租金最低的内窗房，面积在 20 平左右，也需要 3000 以上。有外窗的普遍都在 3800-4000 向上。商业水电。</p><h3 id="绿地-M-Town"><a href="#绿地-M-Town" class="headerlink" title="绿地 M Town"></a>绿地 M Town</h3><p>绿地和上科大就隔了一条金科路，脚下便是即将开通的 13 号线，交通十分方便。配套有今年夏天刚开的绿地张江缤纷城，里面的餐饮已经比较成熟了。绿地的公寓一共有三栋楼，以 loft 为主。作为一室户的话都是房东把 loft 上下隔开，分作两室。最外面一道门，里面两道门。<br>上下层的房子我都看过，层高非常低。楼上的房子，电灯就在我的眼前，多看几眼肯定会瞎。虽然房东一致口径都是说上下两层等高，但实际体验下来楼下还是比楼上高不少，但也只有两米二三左右。房间非常小，十几平，五脏俱全的话就会十分拥挤。高楼层朝外俯瞰，景色还是比较美丽的。我看的几个房子装潢都比较简陋，感觉房东并没有怎么用心，随便摆了张床摆张桌子椅子就完事了。勉强塞一个洗衣机在里面，根本就够不到。洗手间干湿不分离。感觉这边的房子主要要看房东，用心装的话住起来会舒服一些，不走心的话也仅仅只能当作一个睡觉的地方。走廊里还有开店的，安全性会打折扣。隔音比较差。简装的租金普遍在 3000-3200 左右，稍微好些的要 3500 向上。商业水电。</p><h3 id="盛大天地青春里"><a href="#盛大天地青春里" class="headerlink" title="盛大天地青春里"></a>盛大天地青春里</h3><p>青春里是盛大集团自己开发的房子，也分为两处：一处在居里路，称为居里寓。步行到 2 号线金科路站 1 公里左右。由于房源不多，已经我仅仅只看过照片，所以不详细讲了。光看照片的话给人感觉和城家公寓蔡伦路店比较相近，租金一楼朝北 3000，朝南 3200，每往上一层加 200。<br>另外一处在金科路华夏中路东南。可以说一出门就是中环。交通不是很方便，有班车去 2 号线金科路站。肯德基盒马都不送，麦当劳由于在绿地张江缤纷广场新开了一家，所以聊胜于无。青春里有 2 期，15年 1 期刚建好的时候我去玩过，里面有一条商业街，有全家和几个小饭店小面馆。三年多过去了，再去看的时候还是那些店。不过偶尔应付一下应该是够了。<br>1 期 和 2 期大部分都是 loft。所以青春里的招租信息基本都是以找室友为主。不过也有复式的一室户和平层的一室户，比较少。这边的房源分为两块，一块是房东自己买下精装修房，自己或再装一下或原封不动地租出去；另外一种是青春里直接租，没有中介费。一室户直租的价格在 4300 左右，房东租的话会便宜一两百。有的房东会再精装一下作为 airbnb 租出去。房子挺大，40 平多，装潢比较不错，不逊于泊寓万科店。隔音尚可，配有洗衣机和冰箱。小区里整体素质还可以，养宠物的有不少。商业水电。</p><p>做一个直观的比较吧（仅限于一室户）<br>交通：绿地 M Town = 城家公寓科苑路店 &gt; 居里寓 &gt; 城家公寓蔡伦路店 &gt; 泊寓国创店 &gt; 万科翡翠公园 = 泊寓万科店 &gt; 青春里<br>环境：万科翡翠公园 = 泊寓万科店 &gt; 绿地 M Town = 泊寓国创店 &gt; 青春里 &gt; 居里寓 &gt; 城家公寓科苑路店 &gt; 城家公寓蔡伦路店<br>商业：万科翡翠公园 = 泊寓万科店 &gt; 绿地 M Town &gt; 城家公寓科苑路店 &gt; 泊寓国创店 &gt; 青春里 &gt; 居里寓 &gt; 城家公寓蔡伦路店<br>装潢：青春里 = 泊寓万科点 &gt; 城家公寓蔡伦路店 = 居里寓 &gt; 泊寓国创店 &gt; 万科翡翠公园 = 城家公寓科苑路店 &gt; 绿地 M Town<br>价格：泊寓万科店 = 青春里 &gt; 万科翡翠公园 = 泊寓国创店 = 城家公寓科苑路店 &gt; 城家公寓蔡伦路店 &gt; 居里寓 = 绿地 M Town</p><h2 id="张江人才公寓"><a href="#张江人才公寓" class="headerlink" title="张江人才公寓"></a>张江人才公寓</h2><p>除了商业公寓，另外一种选择就是人才公寓。人才公寓的好处和风险前文也已经讲过，这边就不再赘述。主要还是像谈一谈不同地方的人才公寓的特点和区别。忘了提一句，人才公寓都是不配洗衣机冰箱微波炉的，而且都是商业水电。</p><h3 id="高科苑"><a href="#高科苑" class="headerlink" title="高科苑"></a>高科苑</h3><p>高科苑在复旦张江校区和曙光医院的对面，可以说日常的餐饮娱乐包括医疗都十分方便。周围没有商业，但凭借着强大的公交网去 2 号线金科路站和张江高科站也是十分方便。高科苑给人的感觉和住宅小区并无二样，楼层不高，楼间距很大，有老人遛小孩有年轻人遛狗，整体比较静谧祥和。一室户比较少，主要以多室户合租为多。房屋里面装修十分朴素，家具简陋，但是空间巨大。我看过一间一室户的房子，有 60 多平，标准一厅一室一卫一厨一阳台，一个人住怕是还撑不起来。一室户的价格大约在 3000-4000 左右。</p><h3 id="天之骄子"><a href="#天之骄子" class="headerlink" title="天之骄子"></a>天之骄子</h3><p>天之骄子比较远，离 2 号线广兰路有六七百米的距离，和泊寓国创店一河之隔。我是一个礼拜五下班时候去的，周边繁忙程度远超我的想象。天之骄子给人一种大学校园的感觉，里面的住户都比较年轻，傍晚三三两两的在小区内散步。最中间是健身房和室内篮球场，也有人在打羽毛球。配套的餐饮和零售很丰富，满足日常的需要。虽然室内不配有洗衣机，但在篮球场旁有专门的洗衣房，洗衣机和烘干机都有，投币刷卡式的。走在里面真的有一种回到大学校园的错觉（不是指上科大，可能是高中幻想的大学的样子）。<br>室内装潢和城家公寓蔡伦路店相近，只有一张床和一个沙发，其它所有的都要自己配。有个小阳台。隔音没有体验，应该还行。一室户的价格在 3200-3700 之间。</p><h3 id="复旦人才公寓"><a href="#复旦人才公寓" class="headerlink" title="复旦人才公寓"></a>复旦人才公寓</h3><p>复旦人才公寓紧挨着复旦张江校区药学院，南边就是川杨河，交通稍有不便。里面基本没有单独的一室户，而且很少有空房出来，所以没有去看。感兴趣的可以自己关注一下。</p><h3 id="张江豪臣汤园"><a href="#张江豪臣汤园" class="headerlink" title="张江豪臣汤园"></a>张江豪臣汤园</h3><p>张江豪臣汤园和复旦人才公寓类似，没有单独的一室户，都是合租。而且不论是住宅还是人才公寓，房内的装潢总是给人一种浓浓的土味。合租的一室户一般也要 3000 向上。优点是出门即是 2 号线金科路站，交通商业都是顶级。</p><h2 id="后记"><a href="#后记" class="headerlink" title="后记"></a>后记</h2><p>张江租房困难，一是公司太多，住宅公寓太少；二是在张江上班的基本都是高新技术产业，薪水普遍不低。所以张江的房租并不便宜。稍微远一些的可以考虑孙桥、北蔡，有（电动）车一族可以考虑周浦、康桥、唐镇和川沙，都会是很不错的选择。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;前言&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#前言&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;前言&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;前言&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;从十一月份开始，我在张江找了近一个月的房子。要求是独立的一室户，洗手间干湿分离。期间基本把张江这一带符合要求的房子都跑遍了。正好最近有朋友也有类似的需求，那就分享一下经验吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;张江这边能提供一室户的主要有三大类：商业公寓，人才公寓，以及民用住宅。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;商业公寓主要有城家公寓、泊寓、盛大天地青春里、绿地 M Town、万科翡翠公园。这些都是开发商或自己新建或承包已有的老住宅楼自己办的公寓。各家与各家之间不太一样，底下会详谈。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;人才公寓指张江人才公寓，属于公租房。一般来讲都是周围符合要求的上班族或引进的人才通过申请才能拿到，排队时长大多都在一年到两年不等。有一些人在排到的时候，由于自己本身的房子还有租约，或者嫌麻烦不想搬，一般会选择转租。&lt;br&gt;  这种还是存在一定的风险，因为按规定是不允许转租的，网络上还有消息说会有人不定期查房登记。有可能今天人家查了，明天就得搬。不过也有许多人住在里面并没有出现过问题。有的人才公寓会存在最长租期的问题，因为政策原因，可能房东本人只能签两年，到期之后就不能续租了，或是一定期限以后房东公司发的补贴停止，所以租金会有上涨。看房的时候需要问清楚。但由于租金较为便宜，且邻居素质普遍不差，所以还是可以考虑一下的。&lt;br&gt;  人才公寓有好几个，转租比较多的主要是高科苑、天之骄子、张江豪臣汤园以及复旦人才公寓。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;img src=&quot;/2018/12/18/张江一室户租房指南/maps.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;张江人才公寓分布图&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;民用住宅基本都是好几室的那种，一户承包一间卧室或客厅，（有机率）共用洗手间和厨房。基本分布在张江核心区周边，且都是成片的大住宅区，生活气息浓厚，公共交通拥挤。比较有名的如孙桥镇附近的川杨新苑、申城佳苑、玉兰香苑，及张江镇上大片的老小区。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;万科翡翠公园和张江豪臣汤园的情况比较特殊，都有公寓和民住的部分。下文里会谈到。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;由于我自己不愿意和别人合租，所以基本只看了非合租的一室户。下面来讲一讲。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Life" scheme="http://lacroqueta.me/tags/Life/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>最近的两件小事</title>
    <link href="http://lacroqueta.me/2018/10/08/%E6%9C%80%E8%BF%91%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%A4%E4%BB%B6%E5%B0%8F%E4%BA%8B/"/>
    <id>http://lacroqueta.me/2018/10/08/最近的两件小事/</id>
    <published>2018-10-08T14:17:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-10-25T11:33:53.680Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>最近发生的两件事。准确的说是发现。</p><p>F 和我的好友 W 初中做过一年同学，之后 W 转校走了。F 爱慕他，没想到三年后又重新成为了同学。F 一直将这份情愫埋在心底，而 W 在高考后与 F 的朋友 C 互生情愫。大一暑假时，C 过生日，拉了二十几位好友一起出游。当时许多人看着 W 小心翼翼地从自己的包中拿出亲手制作的生日礼物，眼里只有 C 的模样，各有各的羡慕，却无人知道旁观者中 F 是怎样的五味杂陈。后来 C、W 二人分手，W 撰一长文，情深意切，令人唏嘘。F 看罢后也悄悄做了一长文，三年后被我偶然撞见。夜深读此文，每一词每一句都是伤心与不甘。虽然已是陈年往事，但仿佛就在昨日，令人唏嘘。</p><p>无独有偶，我有初中同学 X、H、Z。X 和 Z 是最好的闺蜜，我和 H 是最好的朋友。我们四人位置相邻，关系也算不错。毕业后 H 在空间上向 Z 委婉表白，并无下文。直到前两天看 X 的文章，里面只淡淡的提到了一句话：又梦见10年前喜欢的男孩子。看上下文是 H 无疑。H 当时表白的语句下，曾是有 X 玩笑式的评论的，没曾想其中竟有如此曲折。H 和 X 之后都各自谈过朋友，我们也丝毫没有看出一点端倪。X 只在文章的末尾提到这件事，“我们快要有十年没有见面了。”</p><p>深深埋藏的情愫无人知晓，无人理解，无人回答。自己爱慕的人喜欢的却是自己的好友，欢笑着揶揄着祝福着的同时，只能把苦水自己咽下。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;最近发生的两件事。准确的说是发现。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F 和我的好友 W 初中做过一年同学，之后 W 转校走了。F 爱慕他，没想到三年后又重新成为了同学。F 一直将这份情愫埋在心底，而 W 在高考后与 F 的朋友 C 互生情愫。大一暑假时，C 过生日，拉了二十几位好友一起出游。
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Chatting" scheme="http://lacroqueta.me/tags/Chatting/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MacOS 10.14 &quot;Mojave&quot; Wallpaper</title>
    <link href="http://lacroqueta.me/2018/09/26/mojave/"/>
    <id>http://lacroqueta.me/2018/09/26/mojave/</id>
    <published>2018-09-26T12:32:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-09-26T13:28:56.235Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>MacOS 新一代系统 Mojave 中，出现了动态壁纸，来自加州的沙漠 Mojave。</p><p>动态壁纸可以在一天内的不同时刻自动发生变化。油管上有视频动态展现了整个过程，18秒带你走完一整个周期。</p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HFphX4dpAHk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>MacOS 的壁纸文件存放在 /Library/Desktop Pictures 中，后缀名为 .heic。直接用 Preview 打开，可以发现，一共有16张壁纸。平均下来应该是1.5小时切换一次。然而在实际的体验中发现，壁纸的切换时间并不完全固定，短则半小时，长则好几个小时。或许是因为如黄昏时段景色变化迅速，而夜晚时分则比较稳定，而且大部分人都没有深夜工作欣赏壁纸的习惯吧。</p><p>Reddit 上有大神提取出了这16张壁纸文件，压缩成包供大家下载观摩。于是我也下了一份，受以前看过的以同一角度不同时间取景的图片的启发，动用了落灰已久的 Photoshop，使用最初级的方法合成了一张类似的图片。（笔者在 Windows 操作系统下进行的90%的图片处理都是通过画图软件完成的。）合成之后感觉比较乱，果然理想和现实还是有所差距。</p><p><img src="/2018/09/26/mojave/mojave-c-blog.png" alt="&quot;Mojave&quot;"></p><center><a href="https://files.rb.gd/mojave_dynamic.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mojave 16张壁纸 .zip 文件下载</a></center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;MacOS 新一代系统 Mojave 中，出现了动态壁纸，来自加州的沙漠 Mojave。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;动态壁纸可以在一天内的不同时刻自动发生变化。油管上有视频动态展现了整个过程，18秒带你走完一整个周期。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;3
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Photos" scheme="http://lacroqueta.me/tags/Photos/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Connectome: From Structure to Function</title>
    <link href="http://lacroqueta.me/2018/09/13/Connectome/"/>
    <id>http://lacroqueta.me/2018/09/13/Connectome/</id>
    <published>2018-09-13T14:37:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-10-10T06:49:20.596Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This essay was for the midterm examination of curriculum <em>Introduction to Neuroscience</em> when I was in my junior year of university. It took me about one month to read over 50 papers, and two weeks to draft and to complete. It is still easy to read and understand, in my opinion, and scientific enough to give you the overview of the connectome. Hope you all enjoy it.</p><p><img src="/2018/09/13/Connectome/connectome.png" alt="&quot;test&quot;"></p><center>From <a href="http://www.humanconnectomeproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Human Connectome Project</a></center><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p>Our brain is a complicated network which is unified for structural and functional system. However, currently our knowledge is fairly scarce, while it is essential to learn our brain for the progress of humanity. This article will introduce the concept, meanwhile also an undergoing project, called the connectome. The background and history of connectome are set out first, from the time when Cajal opened the new door of brain science, to one decade ago when this concept was put forward to the public. Then three scales are briefly introduced which is divided to do the research more efficiently, on the basis of the structure and imaging resolution. In addition, the techniques and approaches utilized and the tendency they may development towards are illustrated as well. Finally,  a general conclusion on connectome is made, including the current applications and bright prospects which is to be seen recently and in the future.</p><a id="more"></a><h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>Networks are everywhere nowadays. When we pick up a fallen leaf, we can see the veins on it, which is the network under the leaf surface. When we go out of our house, facing toward our destination, there is a big network consisting of roads and intersections in front of us. And of course, the Internet, which we are both familiar and strange with. For most of us, we use it every day, without knowing what the certain principles is inside. Therefore, we may get kind of helpless, even a little bit desperate, when something is wrong with the Internet, with nobody owing professional knowledge around. For human being, Internet, once created by our own hand, is so complicated that we struggled to learn to learn it. Let alone those networks that were masterpieces created by the nature and is still largely unknown to us. </p><p>In our brain, there exists a mysterious network. As we all know, the most functional unit of our brain is one type of cell, called neurons. There are millions of neurons in human’s brain, making it obvious that some certain interconnections and interactions must exist between the massive individuals. One neuron is composed of soma, axons and dendrites. The information transports from one neuron to another through synapses, which are formed by axons from one neuron and dendrites from another. Several neurons collaborate, to function as a circuit. Several circuits collaborate, to function as a sub-area of the brain. Several sub-areas collaborate, to make our brains work. </p><p>The term “Connectome” was first seen in 2005, suggested by Dr. Olaf Sporns at Indiana University and Dr. Patric Hagmann at Lausanne University Hospital. The connectome is a comprehensive map of neural connections in the brain. As Dr. Olaf Sporns wrote in his paper, “The connectome will significantly increase our understanding of how functional brain states emerge from their underlying structural substrate and will provide new mechanistic insights into how brain function is affected if this structural substrate is disrupted. It will provide a unified, time-invariant, and readily available neuroinformatic resources that could be used in virtually all areas of experimental and theoretical neuroscience.’’<sup>1</sup></p><p>In fact, the term is inspired by genome, another ongoing project with periodic fruit. The two subjects are indeed comparable. Dr. Patric Hagmann pointed out the similarities between genome and connectome in his paper, “It is clear that, like the genome, which is much more than just a juxtaposition of genes, the set of all neuronal connections in the brain is much more than the sum of their individual components. The genome is an entity itself, as it is from the subtle gene interaction that life emerges. In a similar manner, one could consider the brain connectome, set of all neuronal connections, as one single entity, thus emphasizing the fact that the huge brain neuronal communication capacity and computational power critically relies on this subtle and incredibly complex connectivity architecture.”<sup>2</sup></p><p>As is mentioned above, there are quite many similarities between connectome and genome. At first, they are both fundamental structural data sets with regard to the unit they function. Also, there are many levels in the two concepts, especially according to different scales, with synapse, neurons, circuits and sub-region in connectome, while with nucleotide, histones, genes, and chromosome in genome. Thirdly, both of them are different across different species, or different individuals of the same species, or the same species from different period in the long river of time. In addition, although in one individual, they are variable, probably due to environment, requirements for different functions or the spatial proximity.<sup>3-5</sup> At last, complex system dynamics are produced, for instance, the firing patterns of neurons and the spatiotemporal expression of genes.<sup>6</sup></p><p>Just like the time when the genome project first came up, there are many objections and worries against the connectome project, such as insight limitation, poor using of scarce source, seeming impossible task and so on.<sup>7</sup> Anyway so far there have been some achievements towards the goal. About 30 years ago, a work which was consistent with the connectome virtually have been accomplished. The structure of the nervous system of <em>C. elegans</em> was fully constructed.<sup>8-10</sup> There are exactly 302 neurons, without varying structures in <em>C. elegans</em>, making it convenient for study. Although the structure of the nervous system of nematode is much simpler than other species, especially the mammals, the complete data set is still too huge to be handled. Furthermore, partial connectomes of a mouse retina and that of a mouse primary visual cortex have been reconstructed.<sup>11,12</sup> What’s more, in 2014, The Allen Mouse Brain Connectivity Atlas presented a mesoscale connectivity of the adult mouse brain, which is available as an open-access public database.<sup>13</sup></p><p>The ultimate goal is to reconstruct human connectome, which is, “a comprehensive structural description of the network of elements and connections forming the human brain.”<sup>1,2</sup> There is no doubt that the project is significant for us human being. Only if we know what the structure of our brain is like, can we say it is possible to learn the unambiguous function. Otherwise, everything we are doing is just like blind monks touching the elephant to try to depict it, without any directions or strategies or efficiency. There are many groups devoting themselves to explore the secret of human connectome, while two of them in the lead, both of which were awarded Human Connectome Project (HCP) granted by NIH in 2010. One is led by Washington University, the University of Minnesota, and Oxford University, called the “Wu-Minn” HCP consortium, and the other is led by Massachusetts General Hospital and University of California at Los Angeles, called the MGH-UCLA HCP consortium.<sup>14</sup></p><h2 id="Scales-and-Levels"><a href="#Scales-and-Levels" class="headerlink" title="Scales and Levels"></a>Scales and Levels</h2><p>As is similar to genome, which can be studied in different scales of base pairs, nucleotides, genes, chromosomes and so on, there are different scales to watch the connectome. Generally speaking, these scales can be categorized as microscale, mesoscale, and macroscale, intelligible as the name suggests, defined according to different levels of spatial resolution in brain imaging. Different scales provide different fundamental units and elements to study, different methods to utilize, different challenges to face, and different results to get in the end. As a result of that it is quite significant for us to learn about what the certain scales are, and what information they can provide. </p><h3 id="Microscale"><a href="#Microscale" class="headerlink" title="Microscale"></a>Microscale</h3><p>It is the most exquisite scale among the three mentioned above, which means the units and elements we are facing is the most fundamental. It is a world between neurons and synapses, just like what we see under the electron microscope. In microscale, we need to know every interaction between every neuron. It is not as simple as one-to-one correspondence. As we all know, the axon of one neuron forms synapses with the spines of the dendrites on another neuron. The problem is, there are many spines on one dendrite, and there are many dendrites on one neuron. Besides, there can be multiple spots which is capable for forming synapse on one axon terminate, as is suggested in rodent mesoaccumbens axons.<sup>15</sup></p><p>The consequence is that there are about 10<sup>10</sup> neurons in human cerebral cortex, and 10<sup>14</sup> synaptic connections between them.<sup>16</sup> For now, there is no efficient techniques and to do the mass data collection, and we also have no reliable method or theory to do the data analyzing. In addition, the synaptic structures are variable though different times,<sup>3,17</sup> which lifts the dimensions of the problem itself and the difficulties for multiple levels. It seems that the variable remodeling of spines may have an influence on the synaptic connections of abundant potential synaptic sites.<sup>1,18,19</sup> In conclusion, apart from the difficulties we may come across while studying connectome in the microscale, the necessity and effectiveness are also worth questioning. </p><h3 id="Macroscale"><a href="#Macroscale" class="headerlink" title="Macroscale"></a>Macroscale</h3><p>According to the normal logic, the order in which I introduce the three scales is from the smallest to the biggest, or the reverse. However, once upon I finished the microscale part, preparing for the mesoscale part in details, I found the concept of mesoscale is ambiguous, while that of macroscale is much clearer. It is like the two sides are almost decided, so there is much space for the middle to adjust itself. As a result, I decided to change my order, putting the macroscale part in front of the mesoscale part.</p><p>Although the neurons have their own significance in the whole system, some of them have very common points that make them work collaboratively, implementing different functions. If we recognize these similar neurons as a whole part, the brain can be briefly divided into several regions, with their own significance of existing and function. The earliest classification of brain regions is developed by Franz Joseph in the nineteenth century. He came up with a discipline called phrenology, divided the brain into several regions marking different mental functions, like ideality, hope and consciousness.<sup>20</sup> As our knowledge about brain gets deeper, the division of brain regions have been modified for many times. The basis of the division of the brain region is that all the “structural elements share highly similar long-range connectivity patterns”, and that “these patterns are dissimilar between brain regions”.<sup>1</sup> Anyway, no matter how the regions change, they are the nodes that make up the brain graph in macroscale. </p><h3 id="Mesoscale"><a href="#Mesoscale" class="headerlink" title="Mesoscale"></a>Mesoscale</h3><p>As is mentioned above, the definition of mesoscale is quite ambiguous, between those of microscale and macroscale. However, many scientists prefer the word “neuron population” to define the tricky concept.<sup>1,6,13,21</sup> It is under a spatial resolution of hundreds of micrometers, containing hundreds or thousands of individual neurons. According to Dr. Olaf Sporns, the definition of cortical minicolumn is an appropriate example.<sup>1</sup> The dimeter of one minicolumn is about 30-50 micrometers, containing approximately 80-100 individual neurons.<sup>22</sup> As the same as the rule of macroscale, it is also required to be highly similar with the others in one area, and to show difference compared to external properties. </p><p>It is no doubt that the mesoscale and macroscale view are the best two for connectome studying. And in fact, there has been some effectual practice in these two scales. A mesoscale connectome of the mouse brain has been reconstructed by Allen Institute for Brain Science,<sup>13</sup> and was further later.<sup>23</sup> The macroscale connectivity are also be visualized in mouse<sup>24</sup> and human brain.<sup>25</sup> It is believed that the combination of data of connectivity in micro-, meso-, and macroscale will be complementary to each other, making it more convenient, comprehensive, and deep for us to understand the connectome. </p><h2 id="Techs-and-Methods"><a href="#Techs-and-Methods" class="headerlink" title="Techs and Methods"></a>Techs and Methods</h2><p>In the recent one century, scientists who are studying the connectivity of neurons in the brain have used three main methods, the single-cell impregnation, the optically based tract-tracing and electron microscopy.<sup>26</sup> These methods have helped us solve many problems and make the great discoveries, yet, may have more and more drawbacks and restrictions as the technology and our work progresses. In this part, I will introduce some current methods, including but not limited to those mentioned above, and some ideal ones.</p><p>The single-cell staining by dye impregnation is the very first approach to study the brain. It can be traced back to the nineteenth century, when Cajal began to watch the nervous system using Golgi staining. It is known what happened next, and where are standing is based on the great discovery and the great approach. Nevertheless, in spite of its contribution, staining, whether the past or current method, has still not solved some problems. Firstly, because of the light diffraction, there cannot be a high resolution, which makes it impossible to discern in a subtle degree. Secondly, the distance that the chemicals can travel is limited, making it too hard to see the overall situation to make an accurate judgement.</p><p>To make the long-distance observation feasible, scientists then used tract-tracing techniques, in which surgeries were usually required. Afterwards, it was replaced by techniques in which labels was put in certain areas and then diffused to the target regions. There is a wide range of labels, such as radioactive amino acids or sugars, proteins, enzymes and fluorescent organic molecules.<sup>27</sup> As the genetic approaches developments, labels like fluorescent proteins can be encoded in certain times or regions to express, under the control of regulatory elements or viral vectors.<sup>26,28-32</sup> However, a coin has its two sides. Tract-tracing techniques can only trace large neuron populations and single neural pathways, which makes it not so useful if not combining with other complementary approaches.</p><p>For another, electron microscopy can resolve the resolution problem, for it is the most observing techniques nowadays. Electron microscopy played an important role in the construction of connectome of <em>C. elegans</em> in 1986.<sup>8,33</sup> For now, there are many modified combinational methods on the basis of observing via the electron microscopy. Just like 3D print, we can put the tissue into very thin slices, watching and analyzing the information on each individual slice, finally reconstructing them. A new technique utilizing a tape-like structure, makes the cutting and collecting consecutive and automated.<sup>34</sup> Nevertheless, more delicate, more work. Using the slices, which is full of detailed information, means unimaginable information to collect, analyze and integrate. At least currently, it seems lack of hope to do the huge work with techniques we master, let alone by hand. </p><p>In addition, there is also a problem that the construction of the nerve system requires explicit identification of each neurons we are interested. The process cannot be done if there is only one or two single labels being used. Brainbow is such an approach that aiming at this problem. Just as its name, which is inspired by rainbow, a beautiful seven-color natural phenomenon, the function if brainbow is to label individual neurons in stochastic colors, via the expression of multiple fluorescent proteins.<sup>35</sup> The Human Connectome Project even makes a gallery to exhibit the gorgeous artwork-like pictures which shows the structure of the white matter in colors. However, as many other approaches, brainbow has its own limitations. For instance, the diffraction-limited resolution is still a problem. Also, the effect of color display needs to be improved further, such as the brightness, distinguishing degree. What’s more, the expression in projection neurons are high, while that in interneurons are poor.<sup>36</sup></p><p>Inspired by brainbow, here came a novel approach called BOINC, which stands for barcoding of individual neuronal connections.<sup>37</sup> This approach utilizes the convenience and speediness of DNA sequencing. Each neuron is labeled by a unique sequence of nucleotides, just like a barcode. And these barcodes from neurons which are synaptically connected are associated together. As a result, the two types of barcodes, representing one neuron in a sense, is paired, and then be sequenced of high throughput. It is considered to be potential to be cheap and fast.</p><p>It seems there is a lot of work that has been and is being done. However, those works are on the basis of static state. Imaging is not a gif-format animation, or a movie. It can only capture a stop motion for a very short-time moment. For another reason, currently most of the imaging works are conducted post mortem, which means we cannot adjust our experiments for further study, on the same individual, much less real-time monitoring. Some non-invasive imaging techniques provide new approaches about solving the problem.</p><p>MRI, the abbreviation of magnetic resonance imaging, has been a traditional and common approach for imaging the modality of brain.<sup>38</sup> It doesn’t use ionizing radiation, and the data it acquired can be applied for both clinical and research subjects. Repeated scanning of the same individual is also viable. However, the drawback is a long-time stationary state is required, which is difficult for animals. Anyway, MRI provides a basic tech platform that many other techniques are born from it, like dMRI, standing for diffusion MRI, and fMRI, standing for functional MRI.<sup>39</sup> The first provides cubic-millimeter-resolution construction of white-matter tracts,<sup>25</sup> while the second makes it feasible to capture the activity of the brain, revealing a universal functional architecture.<sup>40</sup></p><p>As we acquire structural and functional data, it is time to combine them with some appropriate logic and methods. Four steps are needed to achieve this goal.<sup>41</sup> Firstly, it is essential to determine the parcellation of the brain, and then obtain the data for both structural and functional aiming approaches. Secondly, express the structural linkage and functional coupling. Thirdly, build a connection matrix aggregating both the structural and functional network. Lastly, network analysis can be started by computing and extracting relevant information from the two matrix.<sup>6</sup></p><p>It is obviously not enough to achieve human connectome. The follow-up work was suggested by Dr. Olaf Sporns in his milestone-like paper in 2005.<sup>1</sup> After obtaining the data from network analysis, it is required to test and verify the human connectome. We can perform population analysis of healthy subjects and spatial registration to adjust the result acquired by all of computing to the reality. In addition, we can compare connectome of healthy human with that of patients or compare connectome of human being with that of other species evolutionally next to us, like the macaque. There is inestimable information and value waiting to be discovered.</p><h2 id="Challenges"><a href="#Challenges" class="headerlink" title="Challenges"></a>Challenges</h2><h3 id="Complexity"><a href="#Complexity" class="headerlink" title="Complexity"></a>Complexity</h3><p>As is through the whole article, the reason we spent decades and decades, centuries and centuries, on observing, depicting, dividing and analyzing the brain, and the reason we have and still being developed techniques and approaches one after another, and the reason we are making new discoveries, overthrowing and pruning the previous view, is not only the brain is so important to us, but also it is so complex and variable. The complexity has been involved above but is far more than that. For any levels in the system, ranging from neurons to brain region, is much more complicated than we could imagine. For instance, we are devoting to finding the connections between the structure and function. However, there is a large number of functional connections between regions that are not directedly connect, in anatomical view.<sup>42</sup> The complexity increases the difficulty for us to observe the structure, dispose the data, look for the latent connections, select the appropriate approach, learn and understand the function. </p><h3 id="Individual-Variability"><a href="#Individual-Variability" class="headerlink" title="Individual Variability"></a>Individual Variability</h3><p>Just like the genome, connectome represents a relatively common characteristic of one specie. However, as to individuals, they can have their own connectome. As we all know, everybody of us are different from others’, for we have our own DNA, which carries our own genetic material. The DNA determines what our connectome is like, so our own connectome is different from others’. Apart from genetic differences, there are many other causes resulting in individual connectome variable, such as developmental and experiential history, gender difference, pathologies and responses to injury.<sup>1</sup> If connectome is anticipated to make contributions to certain areas, such as diseases, the individual variability cannot be neglected. </p><h3 id="Parcellations-and-Scales"><a href="#Parcellations-and-Scales" class="headerlink" title="Parcellations and Scales"></a>Parcellations and Scales</h3><p>Another challenge is the criterion of parcellations and scales of the brain. Although there are three recognized relatively clear scales, a certain level of resolution to complete the connectome is still under the debate. With current techniques, we may begin the project from mesoscale and macroscale. It can be foreseen that as we learn more about the nerve system, especially the tinier functional structure than synapses, or even, transmitters, and as we invent more powerful machines and tools, there seems to be an endless processing. And the parcellation also matters, for whether the accurate boundaries of different regions can be found. The lack of knowledge to our brain is the restrictions to achieve the goal, which needs more work along with the whole brain science.</p><h3 id="Techs"><a href="#Techs" class="headerlink" title="Techs"></a>Techs</h3><p>In essence, the lack of knowledge is due to the undeveloped technology. Currently, the acquisition, storage and manipulation of raw data is still a headache problem. It is estimated that a single microscale human connectome may take up one trillion gigabytes.<sup>43</sup> There are also a large number of choke points on our way leading to the truth. As to connectome, there are majorly two types of techniques that are badly required. One is imaging, which can make it clear at a very high resolution, identifying different components at the same time, and the other is analyzing, making it automated and highly efficient to processing abundant data set. Looking back on the history of neuroscience, or a bit wider, the bioscience, each breakthrough made to the field and for human, always came after a new revolutionary technique. The only way to make a breakthrough is the invention of new techniques. Particularly outstanding discoveries and outcomes cannot be made if the technology doesn’t make any progress. </p><h2 id="Outcome"><a href="#Outcome" class="headerlink" title="Outcome"></a>Outcome</h2><p>The direction from basic research for brain science to connectome is no doubt correct. Brain plays such an important role that if the relationship between its structure and function is figured out, imagine what great changes will be brought to our lives! Our intelligence may improve, and we may even amend the personalities that we do not want. We can even get to know what happens in our brain when we are retrieving our certain memory. If you have seen the famous science fiction TV serious <em>Black Mirror</em>, you may not be strange to the scene that the roles in one episode can reviewing and deleting their memory, as seems fantastic but possibly come true someday in the future. Moreover, some serious diseases, like the Parkinson’s disease and the tristimania, may be cured. Several progresses have been made through recent years such as the disorder connectivities of brain in Schizophrenia,<sup>44</sup> and aging.<sup>45</sup> It is also possible for disabled people who have lost their fingers or hands to regain the ability to seize tiny things. The potential of connectome is difficult to estimate and imagine, and so is the profit that can be brought to us. What we are waiting for is a revolutionary researching system, or just an approach, to help us integrating and analyzing the massive raw data. The day when comes the revolution, is the day when we decipher our brain, and is the day when we can change the world.</p><h2 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference"></a>Reference</h2><p>1          Sporns, O., Tononi, G. &amp; Kotter, R. The human connectome: A structural description of the human brain. <em>PLoS Comput Biol</em> <strong>1</strong>, e42, doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.0010042 (2005).</p><p>2          Hagmann, P. <em>From diffusion MRI to brain connectomics</em>, Institut de traitement des signaux PROGRAMME DOCTORAL EN INFORMATIQUE ET COMMUNICATIONS POUR L’OBTENTION DU GRADE DE DOCTEUR ÈS SCIENCES PAR Docteur en médecine, Université de Lausanne, (2005).</p><p>3          Bonhoeffer, T. &amp; Yuste, R. Spine motility. Phenomenology, mechanisms, and function. <em>Neuron</em> <strong>35</strong>, 1019-1027 (2002).</p><p>4          Fraga, M. F. <em>et al.</em> Epigenetic differences arise during the lifetime of monozygotic twins. <em>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</em> <strong>102</strong>, 10604-10609, doi:10.1073/pnas.0500398102 (2005).</p><p>5          Rajapakse, I., Scalzo, D., Tapscott, S. J., Kosak, S. T. &amp; Groudine, M. Networking the nucleus. <em>Mol Syst Biol</em> <strong>6</strong>, 395, doi:10.1038/msb.2010.48 (2010).</p><p>6          Sporns, O. The human connectome: a complex network. <em>Ann N Y Acad Sci</em> <strong>1224</strong>, 109-125, doi:10.1111/j.1749-6632.2010.05888.x (2011).</p><p>7          Lichtman, J. W. &amp; Sanes, J. R. Ome sweet ome: what can the genome tell us about the connectome? <em>Curr Opin Neurobiol</em> <strong>18</strong>, 346-353, doi:10.1016/j.conb.2008.08.010 (2008).</p><p>8          White, J. G., Southgate, E., Thomson, J. N. &amp; Brenner, S. The structure of the nervous system of the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans. <em>Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci</em> <strong>314</strong>, 1-340 (1986).</p><p>9          Chen, B. L.-J. <em>Neuronal network of C. elegans: from anatomy to behavior</em>, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, (2007).</p><p>10        Varshney, L. R., Chen, B. L., Paniagua, E., Hall, D. H. &amp; Chklovskii, D. B. Structural properties of the Caenorhabditis elegans neuronal network. <em>PLoS Comput Biol</em> <strong>7</strong>, e1001066 (2011).</p><p>11        Briggman, K. L., Helmstaedter, M. &amp; Denk, W. Wiring specificity in the direction-selectivity circuit of the retina. <em>Nature</em> <strong>471</strong>, 183-188, doi:10.1038/nature09818 (2011).</p><p>12        Bock, D. D. <em>et al.</em> Network anatomy and in vivo physiology of visual cortical neurons. <em>Nature</em> <strong>471</strong>, 177-182, doi:10.1038/nature09802 (2011).</p><p>13        Oh, S. W. <em>et al.</em> A mesoscale connectome of the mouse brain. <em>Nature</em> <strong>508</strong>, 207-214, doi:10.1038/nature13186 (2014).</p><p>14        Van Essen, D. C. <em>et al.</em> The WU-Minn Human Connectome Project: an overview. <em>Neuroimage</em> <strong>80</strong>, 62-79, doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2013.05.041 (2013).</p><p>15        Zhang, S. <em>et al.</em> Dopaminergic and glutamatergic microdomains in a subset of rodent mesoaccumbens axons. <em>Nat Neurosci</em> <strong>18</strong>, 386-392, doi:10.1038/nn.3945 (2015).</p><p>16        Young, M. P. The organization of neural systems in the primate cerebral cortex. <em>Proc Biol Sci</em> <strong>252</strong>, 13-18, doi:10.1098/rspb.1993.0040 (1993).</p><p>17        Engert, F. &amp; Bonhoeffer, T. Dendritic spine changes associated with hippocampal long-term synaptic plasticity. <em>Nature</em> <strong>399</strong>, 66-70, doi:10.1038/19978 (1999).</p><p>18        Stepanyants, A., Hof, P. R. &amp; Chklovskii, D. B. Geometry and structural plasticity of synaptic connectivity. <em>Neuron</em> <strong>34</strong>, 275-288 (2002).</p><p>19        Kalisman, N., Silberberg, G. &amp; Markram, H. The neocortical microcircuit as a tabula rasa. <em>P Natl Acad Sci USA</em> <strong>102</strong>, 880-885, doi:10.1073/pnas.0407088102 (2005).</p><p>20        Luo, L. <em>Principles of Neurobiology</em>.  (Garland Science, 2015).</p><p>21        Rah, J. C., Feng, L., Druckmann, S., Lee, H. &amp; Kim, J. From a meso- to micro-scale connectome: array tomography and mGRASP. <em>Front Neuroanat</em> <strong>9</strong>, 78, doi:10.3389/fnana.2015.00078 (2015).</p><p>22        Mountcastle, V. B. The columnar organization of the neocortex. <em>Brain</em> <strong>120</strong>, 701-722, doi:DOI 10.1093/brain/120.4.701 (1997).</p><p>23        Henriksen, S., Pang, R. &amp; Wronkiewicz, M. A simple generative model of the mouse mesoscale connectome. <em>Elife</em> <strong>5</strong>, doi:ARTN e12366</p><p>10.7554/eLife.12366 (2016).</p><p>24        Stafford, J. M. <em>et al.</em> Large-scale topology and the default mode network in the mouse connectome. <em>P Natl Acad Sci USA</em> <strong>111</strong>, 18745-18750, doi:10.1073/pnas.1404346111 (2014).</p><p>25        Craddock, R. C. <em>et al.</em> Imaging human connectomes at the macroscale. <em>Nature Methods</em> <strong>10</strong>, 524-539, doi:10.1038/Nmeth.2482 (2013).</p><p>26        Lichtman, J. W., Livet, J. &amp; Sanes, J. R. A technicolour approach to the connectome. <em>Nat Rev Neurosci</em> <strong>9</strong>, 417-422, doi:10.1038/nrn2391 (2008).</p><p>27        Callahan, C. A., Yoshikawa, S. &amp; Thomas, J. B. Tracing axons. <em>Curr Opin Neurobiol</em> <strong>8</strong>, 582-586 (1998).</p><p>28        Feinstein, P., Bozza, T., Rodriguez, I., Vassalli, A. &amp; Mombaerts, P. Axon guidance of mouse olfactory sensory neurons by odorant receptors and the beta 2 adrenergic receptor. <em>Cell</em> <strong>117</strong>, 833-846, doi:DOI 10.1016/j.cell.2004.05.013 (2004).</p><p>29        Bareyre, F. M., Kerschensteiner, M., Misgeld, T. &amp; Sanes, J. R. Transgenic labeling of the corticospinal tract for monitoring axonal responses to spinal cord injury. <em>Nat Med</em> <strong>11</strong>, 1355-1360, doi:10.1038/nm1331 (2005).</p><p>30        Dymecki, S. M. &amp; Kim, J. C. Molecular neuroanatomy’s “three Gs”: A primer. <em>Neuron</em> <strong>54</strong>, 17-34, doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2007.03.009 (2007).</p><p>31        Song, C. K., Enquist, L. W. &amp; Bartness, T. J. New developments in tracing neural circuits with herpesviruses. <em>Virus Res</em> <strong>111</strong>, 235-249, doi:10.1016/j.virusres.2005.04.012 (2005).</p><p>32        Luo, L., Callaway, E. M. &amp; Svoboda, K. Genetic dissection of neural circuits. <em>Neuron</em> <strong>57</strong>, 634-660, doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2008.01.002 (2008).</p><p>33        Macagno, E. R., Levinthal, C. &amp; Sobel, I. Three-dimensional computer reconstruction of neurons and neuronal assemblies. <em>Annu Rev Biophys Bioeng</em> <strong>8</strong>, 323-351, doi:10.1146/annurev.bb.08.060179.001543 (1979).</p><p>34        Kasthuri, N. <em>et al.</em> Saturated Reconstruction of a Volume of Neocortex. <em>Cell</em> <strong>162</strong>, 648-661, doi:10.1016/j.cell.2015.06.054 (2015).</p><p>35        Livet, J. <em>et al.</em> Transgenic strategies for combinatorial expression of fluorescent proteins in the nervous system. <em>Nature</em> <strong>450</strong>, 56-62, doi:10.1038/nature06293 (2007).</p><p>36        Feng, G. <em>et al.</em> Imaging neuronal subsets in transgenic mice expressing multiple spectral variants of GFP. <em>Neuron</em> <strong>28</strong>, 41-51 (2000).</p><p>37        Zador, A. M. <em>et al.</em> Sequencing the connectome. <em>PLoS Biol</em> <strong>10</strong>, e1001411, doi:10.1371/journal.pbio.1001411 (2012).</p><p>38        Barkovich, A. J. <em>Pediatric neuroimaging</em>.  (Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2005).</p><p>39        Tymofiyeva, O., Hess, C. P., Xu, D. &amp; Barkovich, A. J. Structural MRI connectome in development: challenges of the changing brain. <em>Brit J Radiol</em> <strong>87</strong>, doi:ARTN 20140086</p><p>10.1259/bjr.20140086 (2014).</p><p>40        Kelly, C., Biswal, B. B., Craddock, C., Castellanos, F. X. &amp; Milham, M. P. Characterizing variation in the functional connectome: promise and pitfalls. <em>Trends Cogn Sci</em> <strong>16</strong>, 181-188, doi:10.1016/j.tics.2012.02.001 (2012).</p><p>41        Bullmore, E. &amp; Sporns, O. Complex brain networks: graph theoretical analysis of structural and functional systems (vol 10, pg 186, 2009). <em>Nature Reviews Neuroscience</em> <strong>10</strong>, doi:10.1038/nrn2618 (2009).</p><p>42        Horwitz, B., Mcintosh, A. R., Haxby, J. V. &amp; Grady, C. L. Network Analysis of Brain Cognitive Function Using Metabolic and Blood-Flow Data. <em>Behav Brain Res</em> <strong>66</strong>, 187-193, doi:Doi 10.1016/0166-4328(94)00139-7 (1995).</p><p>43        Kasthuri, N. &amp; Lichtman, J. W. Neurocartography. <em>Neuropsychopharmacology</em> <strong>35</strong>, 342-343, doi:10.1038/npp.2009.138 (2010).</p><p>44        Lynall, M. E. <em>et al.</em> Functional Connectivity and Brain Networks in Schizophrenia. <em>Journal of Neuroscience</em> <strong>30</strong>, 9477-9487, doi:10.1523/Jneurosci.0333-10.2010 (2010).</p><p>45        Meunier, D., Achard, S., Morcom, A. &amp; Bullmore, E. T. Age-related changes in modular organization of human brain functional networks. <em>Neuroimage</em> <strong>44</strong>, 715-723, doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.09.062 (2009).</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;This essay was for the midterm examination of curriculum &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; when I was in my junior year of university. It took me about one month to read over 50 papers, and two weeks to draft and to complete. It is still easy to read and understand, in my opinion, and scientific enough to give you the overview of the connectome. Hope you all enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2018/09/13/Connectome/connectome.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;test&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humanconnectomeproject.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Human Connectome Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Abstract&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our brain is a complicated network which is unified for structural and functional system. However, currently our knowledge is fairly scarce, while it is essential to learn our brain for the progress of humanity. This article will introduce the concept, meanwhile also an undergoing project, called the connectome. The background and history of connectome are set out first, from the time when Cajal opened the new door of brain science, to one decade ago when this concept was put forward to the public. Then three scales are briefly introduced which is divided to do the research more efficiently, on the basis of the structure and imaging resolution. In addition, the techniques and approaches utilized and the tendency they may development towards are illustrated as well. Finally,  a general conclusion on connectome is made, including the current applications and bright prospects which is to be seen recently and in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Neuroscience" scheme="http://lacroqueta.me/tags/Neuroscience/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="http://lacroqueta.me/2018/09/12/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://lacroqueta.me/2018/09/12/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2018-09-12T04:10:53.859Z</published>
    <updated>2018-09-15T09:08:49.954Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a>.</p><a id="more"></a><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">"My New Post"</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/deployment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;! This is your very first post. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; or you can ask me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
